const art_questions = [
  {
    question: "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
    answer: "Leonardo da Vinci",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Which art movement is known for its use of bold colors and geometric shapes?",
    answer: "Cubism",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the famous sculpture created by Michelangelo that depicts the Biblical figure David?",
    answer: "David",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Who is considered the father of modern abstract art?",
    answer: "Wassily Kandinsky",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Which artist is known for his surreal and melting clocks in paintings such as 'The Persistence of Memory'?",
    answer: "Salvador Dal√≠",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "What art style is characterized by its emphasis on depicting everyday life and scenes?",
    answer: "Realism",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the famous Japanese contemporary artist known for his polka dot art and pumpkins?",
    answer: "Yayoi Kusama",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Which Renaissance artist sculpted the Statue of David and painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?",
    answer: "Michelangelo",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the Dutch painter known for his use of color in works such as 'Starry Night'?",
    answer: "Vincent van Gogh",
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the American artist famous for his pop art, including works like 'Campbell's Soup Cans'?",
    answer: "Andy Warhol",
    category: "Art"
  }
];

export default art_questions;